topica.com 2015-02-24

# Topica's Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to [www.topica.com](http://www.topica.com/) owned and operated by Topica, Inc. (.Topica.). This privacy policy describes how Topica collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: www.topica.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

Topica is committed to protecting your privacy. We want you to feel free to express yourself on the Topica system, so we are committed to allowing you to feel secure in an environment that puts you in control of what you share with the rest of the community, and with Topica.

Topica will never willfully disclose personally identifiable information about its customers to any third party without first receiving that customer's permission, unless necessary for legal reasons.

What information does Topica collect?  
You don't need to provide any information in order to browse the Topica directory, use the search functionality to find an email newsletter or discussion group, or view the archives of lists that the list publisher has chosen to make public. A public list is one whose archives are readable not only by subscribers, but by any visitor to the Topica site . whether registered or not. On all public lists viewable through the Topica Web site, the email addresses of participants are partially obscured so they are not obtainable by unauthorized visitors. A private list is one whose archives are only accessible to registered Topica users who are subscribed to that list. On both public and private lists, subscribers of any given list have access to one another's email addresses. It is the list owner's choice as to whether a list is public or private.

If you choose to start a list at Topica or subscribe to one, we will ask you to register. During registration, we ask you to provide the following information: name, email address, zip code, birth date, gender and country.

If you choose to sign up for the Topica service, we will ask you to provide the following information: name, company name, email address, credit card type, credit card number, credit card expiration date, name on card, billing address, city, state, country, zip code and phone number. We use this information to provide the services you request, send you notifications about product updates, system events such as downtime, respond to customer support requests, etc. You can access and change your information by logging into your account and going to the "Admin" or "Account" pages. You will also be signed up for the Topica newsletter we send customers, which you can unsubscribe from at any time by clicking on the "unsubscribe" button at the bottom of the message.

We will NOT disclose, sell or exchange your personally identifiable information (name and email address) to or with anyone, without your approval. The only circumstances under which personally identifiable information about Topica users will be shared in a manner inconsistent to that stated above is if we believe disclosure is reasonably necessary to:

  * comply with the law or legal process; 
  * protect or defend the rights or property of Topica or others; 
  * enforce our Terms of Service; or 
  * respond to claims that the content of any communication on the Topica system violates the rights of others.

During registration, you can sign up for deals and offers from Topica partners: third parties with whom Topica has agreements. To activate third-party subscriptions, Topica shares your registration information with only those third parties whose offers you choose. In any case where information is shared, you will see a disclosure statement to that effect. In signing up for offers with such disclosures, you give Topica permission to share the relevant information with the indicated third party.

If you sign up for magazine offers, you will be asked to provide a mailing address. Mailing address information is shared with the magazine publisher and/or distributor in order to fulfill your subscription request.

How does Topica use the information collected?  
We will aggregate user information and perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our members and visitors, to measure overall demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Topica domain and to analyze how and where to use our resources. Topica shares general demographic and interest information with third parties and sales prospects, but such aggregate information is not personally identifiable. We also use the aggregate data collected to inform our sponsors as to the number of people who have seen and "clicked" on their advertisement. In addition, Topica may compile and disclose aggregate information about its users for promotional or other purposes. For example, we might want to disclose that a certain percentage of our users are located within a particular geographic area or fall within a particular age range.

Does Topica use cookies?  
Topica uses both session cookies and persistent cookies (for an explanation of cookies, please see <http://www.epic.org/privacy/internet/cookies/>). Cookies help us determine how long users view particular content, which particular content (e.g., advertising) users view, which content or sites users link to, and which Topica services members and visitors use.

Persistent cookies are used if you choose to enable the auto-login feature. These cookies are randomly generated and uniquely assigned to each user. They are not associated with any personally identifiable information such as name or password.

Session cookies help us keep track of when a person is logged in. Once a user is logged in, session cookies allow us to personalize information on our Web site for them, as well as keep track of lists to which they have subscription privileges.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our Free Discussion List site ([http://lists.topica.com](http://lists.topica.com/)). We have no access to, or control over, these cookies.

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns

How can I change or delete information about me stored at Topica? As a registered Topica user, you have easy access to your information, along with the ability to change it. And, you can always choose to unsubscribe from any list you've signed up to at Topica.

To change or delete personal information: Log in to your "My Topica" account ([http:/lists.topica.com/my/](http://lists.topica.com/my/)). From the Preferences menu on the left, click the Password and User Profile link. Make any changes you like to your user profile, and save them when you are done.

To change your email address: Log in to your "My Topica" account ([http:/lists.topica.com/my/](http://lists.topica.com/my/)). From the Preferences menu on the left, click the Email Addresses link. Follow the instructions on the page to change or delete your email address.

To terminate your Topica service: You may terminate all of your Topica subscriptions and your "My Topica" account by contacting our Customer Care department.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements

How can I unsubscribe from email lists at Topica?  
There are three ways to unsubscribe from Topica lists.

  * Use the Easy Unsubscribe link that appears at the bottom of every message you receive from a Topica list. Clicking the link takes you to an unsubscribe page at the Topica site, where you're asked to confirm that you want to unsubscribe. Click the confirmation link, and you are unsubscribed.
  * Use your "My Topica" account to unsubscribe. Log in to your "My Topica" account ([http:/lists.topica.com/my/](http://lists.topica.com/my/)). Look for the column called "Delivery Method," located to the right of the names of the lists you are subscribed to. Using the drop-down menu in the "Delivery Method" column, highlight "Unsubscribe," then go to the bottom of the page and click the "Save Changes" button.
  * Send an email message to [listname]-unsubscribe@topica.com, where [listname] is replaced by the actual name of the list. For instance, if you were subscribed to a list called CarClub, you could remove yourself from the list by sending a message to the following address: [CarClub-unsubscribe@topica.com](mailto:CarClub-unsubscribe@topica.com)

How does Topica protect the privacy of children?  
As the Topica service is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, there are certain safeguards in place to prevent children from registering with our service. However, as with any Web site, children can access all parts of the site which are accessible to the general public. See the "What information does Topica collect?" section of this document for an explanation of what information is publicly accessible through the Topica site.

Blog/ Forum  
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact our Privacy and Standards department. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why

Links to 3rd Party Sites  
Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Topica. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit

Social Media Widgets  
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Third Party Partners  
We use third parties for the specific services below. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

SalesForce.com  
Topica works with SalesForce.com to organize requests for Sales contacts. If you request that a member of our Sales team contact you, we send your contact and other information to our account at SalesForce.com. SalesForce.com is an application service provider that many companies use to organize call-back requests, etc. They are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

Aptimus, Inc.  
Topica works with Aptimus to provide back-end processing services for our Top Offers mailing list. If you have signed up for the Top Offers newletter, we will transmit your e-mail address and certain other personal data such as name and gender to Aptimus to better deliver our Newsletter. Aptimus is prohibited from using this information for any other purpose.

Separately from this process, Topica also partners with Aptimus to offer Aptimus-sponsored third-party co-registration offers. These offers are labeled as being through Aptimus. Subscribers can choose whether to opt in to the various offers. If a subscriber elects to participate in such an offer, the information they supply through that opt-in process is forwarded to the third-party whose offer(s) the subscriber opts into and to Aptimus for their use. See [Aptimus's Privacy Policy](http://www.aptimus.com/privacy.shtml).

Adteractive  
Topica partners with Adteractive to offer Adteractive-sponsored third-party co-registration offers. These offers are labeled as being through Adteractive. Subscribers can choose whether to opt in to the various offers. If a subscriber elects to participate in such an offer, the information they supply through that opt-in process is forwarded to the third-party whose offer(s) the subscriber opts into and to Adteractive for their use.

Verisign  
Topica uses Verisign to process credit card payments. If you pay for your Topica account by credit card, we send your credit card information to our Verisign account. Verisign is one of the most well-known companies doing credit card processing.

Security Policy  
The security of your personal information is important to us. Our web site protects sensitive information such as your login and credit card information using Internet industry standard encryption protocols to encrypt the information in transit.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, please [contact us.](mailto:privacy@sfo.topica.com)

Notification of Changes  
If Topica intends to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our web site notifying users of the change prior to it becoming effective. In some cases when we post such a notice we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

If you have any questions or comments about this policy, [please contact our Privacy and Standards department](mailto:privacy@sfo.topica.com).

Topica Inc. 1 Post Street, Suite 875, San Francisco, CA 94104, USA
